<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Interview Tips | _here be dragons_]]></title>
  <link href="http://sajithdilshan.github.io/blog/blog/categories/interview-tips/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sajithdilshan.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-12T14:53:58+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sajithdilshan.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sajith Dilshan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facing an Interview]]></title>
    <link href="http://sajithdilshan.github.io/blog/blog/2013/08/11/facing-an-interview/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-11T15:30:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sajithdilshan.github.io/blog/blog/2013/08/11/facing-an-interview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I got the chance to face an interview for the position of a Softwre Engineer, (Intern)  and I thought I would share the details. Hope this would be helpful for anyone who is looking for some tips before going to an interview.</p>

<p>So let&rsquo;s start with the CV. When you&rsquo;re preparing the CV don&rsquo;t include each and every achievement, experience and project you did. CV is mainly a marketing document. Do some research on the company you&rsquo;re applying, and customize your CV so that it only includes relevant data about yourself, which might come in handy if you get to work in that particular company. (E.g. If a company is heavily using a particular framework, emphasis your experience and the projects you did using that framework.)</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re adding a project that you did on the CV, you&rsquo;re expected to answer any question regarding that project. So if you decide to include a group project, you should know all the aspects of it. When the interviewer asks a question about the client-server communication aspect of a particular project, you shouldn&rsquo;t say that &ldquo;I only did the database part and I have no idea about the communication part&rdquo;. It would only display your ignorance and negligence.</p>

<p>And keep in mind to add your interest in the CV too. Don&rsquo;t add a particular topic just because it is the current trend. Instead add topics which are relevant and you&rsquo;re passionate about.</p>

<p>Before going to the interview, polish your knowledge on certain topics like OOP principles, databases, design patterns, algorithms and languages like Java. You can Google and find out what kind of questions are asked frequently in interviews from above topics. And also don&rsquo;t forget to research and get the gist of the technologies which are mostly used by that particular company you&rsquo;re applying.</p>

<p>When going for the interview, wear something simple, but professional. And get to the place at least 15 minutes early. Always be polite, smile, pay your full attention to the interviewer and do not lie under any circumstance. If you don&rsquo;t know the answer to a question, be humble enough to say that you don&rsquo;t know. When answering the questions don&rsquo;t rush, take your time and explain yourself clearly. If you don&rsquo;t understand the question, politely ask to explain it a bit more instead of answering without comprehending the question. Keep in mind that having good communication skills can play a key role in an interview. You might be a really intelligent person, but poor communication skills might let you down. So if you think that there is room for improvements, better get started working on that right away.</p>

<p>Last but not least, and interview is a chance to market yourself and to convince the other party that you&rsquo;re the one they&rsquo;re looking for and you&rsquo;d be  a valuable asset for the company. And if you failed to do that analyze what you did wrong, learn your lessons and be more prepared for the next opportunity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
